JASON KING

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER, FRONTEND ENGINEER

Multi-disciplinary, proactive, problem-solver with agency and start-up background. Self-directed learner able to process sophisticated material and master new concepts and technologies, encapsulate complex processes, and function across disciplines and departments. Client and stakeholder-focused, tolerant of ambiguity; experienced through complete lifecycle development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AdCycle – Full Stack Web Developer, Design Technologist – Princeton, NJ Jul 2018–Present Helped clients develop digital marketing and reporting strategies to drive brand engagement, grow website traffic, and boost sales. Crafted content and user experiences. Provided design and development services.

- Developed custom WordPress sites, implemented SEO strategies, setup web analytics and reporting.
- Integrated and built print-on-demand eCommerce and merchandising solutions in WordPress and Shopify.
- Developed Full-stack HTML5/JavaScript projects and prototypes with libraries and frameworks such as React, Vue, Express.js, NextJS, and MongoDB.

CDM Princeton - Sr. Full Stack Web Developer - Princeton, NJ

Oct 2010-Jul 2018

Lead full-stack developer and system administrator delivering web and mobile UX/UI development, backend application and REST API programming, linux system administration, and continuous integration dev tooling for pharmaceutical clients such as Merck, Gilead, Astra-Zeneca, Novo Nordisk, Shire, BMS, and Watson.

- Increased developer productivity by decoupling front- and backend web development using RESTful APIs to transact data in JSON between HTML/CSS/AngularJS frontends and PHP/Node.js/.NET backends.
- Improved QA and process efficiency by implementing version control, continuous integration, and delivery pipelines and managing connected Linux production and Docker development hosting environments.
- Developed cross-browser, responsive, mobile and desktop frontends, microsites, display advertisements and Veeva/Salesforce-based IVAs via HTML5, CSS3/SASS, and JavaScript/AngularJS/jQuery.
- Architected and developed PHP web service applications to process patient enrollments, generate PDFs, and interface with third-party APIs to transmit enrollment information, faxes, and email.
- Defined and programmed REST APIs using PHP/Laravel, Node.js/Express.js, and MySQL/MongoDB.
- Programmed hybrid mobile apps for iOS, Android, and Blackberry with Cordova and Ionic Framework.
- Designed and built multi-node Proxmox VE cluster; managed Ubuntu and CentOS VMs and Docker nodes.
- Developed projects and performed QA, regression, and cross-browser testing in Agile environment;
- Coordinated with vendors and client IT teams to support timely and reliable rollout of production sites.

Mentored junior developers and assisted with project planning and project management tasks.

Dawson Multimedia – Full Stack Web Developer, UX/UI Specialist – Orlando, FL Jul 2007–Oct 2010

Worked closely with client stakeholders to capture requirements and create project and design specifications aligned with their business needs and marketing strategies.

- · Designed and programmed cross-platform, semantically correct, responsive web and mobile sites.
- Provided web-hosting, email, DNS, SSL, and other IT support services to small business clients.
- Created custom websites, logos, brochures, packaging, and signage for retail and service-industry clients.

Faulkner Press - Full Stack Web Developer - Gainesville, FL

Jul 2005-Jun 2007

Ensured all websites and systems were operational; managed service team; developed new functionality.

 Created PHP/MySQL eCommerce-enabled website and Intranet/Extranet system with course registration, grade-reporting, content publishing services, and customer help-desk.

Ant-Hill - Product Manager, Lead Programmer - Tallahassee, FL

Apr 2003-Jun 2005

Architect and lead developer of web-based payroll platform; managed dev team and operations reliability.

- Performed business requirements analysis, MySQL database design, and SQL implementations.
- Led backend PHP application development and frontend UI scripting in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

University of Florida - Bachelor of Arts - Gainesville, FL

Film & Media Studies / Literary Theory & Criticism